export const data = [
    {
        
        
        question:"What does HTML stand for?",
        option1: "a) Hyper Text Markup Language",
        option2:"b) High Tech Markup Language",
        option3:"c) Hyperlink Text Markup Language",
        option4:"d) Home Tool Markup Language",
        ans:1,

    },
    {
        question:"Which technology is primarily responsible for the styling of web pages?",
        option1: "a) JavaScript",
        option2:"b) HTML",
        option3:"c) CSS",
        option4:"d) Python",
        ans:3,

    },
    {
        question:"Which programming language is mainly used for adding interactivity to websites ?",
        option1: "a) HTML",
        option2:"b) CSS",
        option3:"c) Python",
        option4:"d) JavaScript",
        ans:4,

    },
    {
        question:" What is the purpose of a front-end web development framework like React or Angular?",
        option1: "a) To manage databases and server-side logic",
        option2:"b) To create a visually appealing user interface",
        option3:"c) To handle server-side routing",
        option4:"d) To interact with web servers",
        ans:2,

    },
   
    {
        question:"Which part of web development is responsible for handling data storage and retrieval?",
        option1: "a) Front-end development",
        option2:"b) Back-end development",
        option3:"c) Full-stack development",
        option4:"d) Middleware development",
        ans:2,

    },
    {
        question:"What is the primary function of a web server in the context of web development?",
        option1: "a) Rendering web pages on the client’s browser",
        option2:"b) Executing JavaScript code",
        option3:"c) Storing user data",
        option4:"d) Handling HTTP requests and serving web pages",
        ans:4,

    },
    {
        question:"Which of the following is not a back-end programming language commonly used in web development?",
        option1: "a) PHP",
        option2:"b) Ruby",
        option3:"c) Java",
        option4:"d)  HTML",
        ans:4,

    },
    {
        question:"What is the purpose of the script tag in HTML?",
        option1: " a) To define the page’s structure",
        option2:"b) To include external CSS styles",
        option3:"c) To include external JavaScript code",
        option4:"d) To create hyperlinks",
        ans:3,

    },
    {
        question:"Which HTML tag is used to create a hyperlink?",
        option1: " a) {a}",
        option2:"  b) {link}",
        option3:" c) {h1}",
        option4:"  d) {p}",
        ans:1,

    },
    {
        question:" What is the correct syntax for creating a CSS class called “highlight” with a red text color?",
        option1: "a) .highlight { color: red; }",
        option2:"b) highlight { text-color: red; }",
        option3:"c) .highlight { text-color: red; }",
        option4:"d) highlight { color: red; }",
        ans:1,

    },
    {
        question:" What is the purpose of the “form” element in HTML?:",
        option1: "a) It defines a hyperlink",
        option2:"b) It creates a container for metadata",
        option3:"c) It allows users to input data and submit it to the server",
        option4:"d) It defines a section in a document",
        ans:3,

    },
    {
        question:"Which of the following is used to store and query data in a tabular format in web development?",
        option1: "a) Database",
        option2:"b) API",
        option3:"c) JSON",
        option4:"d) XML",
        ans:1,

    },
    {
        question:"Which JavaScript function is used to change the content of an HTML element?",
        option1: "a) modify()",
        option2:"b) change()",
        option3:"c) update()",
        option4:"d) innerHTML()",
        ans:4,
    },  
    {
        question:" Which of the following is an example of a front-end web development framework/library?",
        option1: "a) Express.js",
        option2:"b) Django",
        option3:"c) Flask",
        option4:"d) React.js",
        ans:4,
    },  
    {
        question:"What is the purpose of the “cookie” in web development?",
        option1: "a) To store data on the client’s browser for future use",
        option2:"b) To encrypt sensitive information during transmission",
        option3:"c) To handle server-side logic",
        option4:"d) To create user authentication systems",
        ans:1,
    },  
    {
        question:"Which CSS property is used to create rounded corners for an HTML element?",
        option1: "a) border-radius",
        option2:"b) corner-radius",
        option3:"c) rounded-corners",
        option4:"d) box-radius",
        ans:1,
    }, 
    {
        question:"Which of the following is NOT a commonly used web development framework for Python?",
        option1: "a) Flask",
        option2:"b) Django",
        option3:"c) Express.js",
        option4:"dd) Pyramid",
        ans:3,
    }, 
    {
        question:"Which CSS property is used to change the font size of text?",
        option1: "a) font-size",
        option2:"b) text-size",
        option3:"c) font-style",
        option4:"d) text-style",
        ans:1,
    }, 
    {
        question:"What is the primary function of a web server in the context of web development?",
        option1: "a) Rendering web pages on the client’s browser",
        option2:"b) Executing JavaScript code",
        option3:"c) Storing user data",
        option4:"d) Handling HTTP requests and serving web pages",
        ans:4,
    }, 
    {
        question:"Which HTML tag is used to define a table in web development?",
        option1: "a) {table}",
        option2:"b) b) {div}",
        option3:"c) {form}",
        option4:"d) {img}",
        ans:1,
    }, 
   
];
